<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright © 2016-2021 The Thingsboard Authors

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<LWM2M xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://openmobilealliance.org/tech/profiles/LWM2M.xsd">
    <Object ObjectType="MODefinition">
        <Name>Interval Data Delivery</Name>
        <Description1><![CDATA[The Interval Data Delivery object provides an optimised means for managing the delivery of interval data from multiple Interval Data Object instances. ]]></Description1>
        <ObjectID>10262</ObjectID>
        <ObjectURN>urn:oma:lwm2m:x:10262</ObjectURN>
        <MultipleInstances>Multiple</MultipleInstances>
        <Mandatory>Optional</Mandatory>
        <Resources>
            <Item ID="0">
                <Name>Name</Name>
                <Operations>RW</Operations>
                <MultipleInstances>Single</MultipleInstances>
                <Mandatory>Mandatory</Mandatory>
                <Type>String</Type>
                <RangeEnumeration></RangeEnumeration>
                <Units></Units>
                <Description><![CDATA[The Name resource provides a way to identify different Interval Data Delivery instances. Name is a readable and writable attribute. Name is defined as an arbitrary length text string]]></Description>
            </Item>
            <Item ID="1">
                <Name>Interval Data Links</Name>
                <Operations>RW</Operations>
                <MultipleInstances>Multiple</MultipleInstances>
                <Mandatory>Mandatory</Mandatory>
                <Type>Objlnk</Type>
                <RangeEnumeration></RangeEnumeration>
                <Units></Units>
                <Description><![CDATA[The Interval Data Links resource is a set of object links that point to each of the Interval Data Object Instances that are managed by this Interval Data Delivery Object Instance. An Object Link is two 16-bit integer values representing the Object ID and the Object Instance ID. This resource can have multiple instances allowing this Interval Data Delivery object to manage many Interval Data instances.]]></Description>
            </Item>
            <Item ID="2">
                <Name>Latest Payload</Name>
                <Operations>R</Operations>
                <MultipleInstances>Multiple</MultipleInstances>
                <Mandatory>Mandatory</Mandatory>
                <Type>Opaque</Type>
                <RangeEnumeration></RangeEnumeration>
                <Units></Units>
                <Description><![CDATA[The Latest Payload resource is a multiple instance resource representing the Latest Payload resource from each of the Interval Data objects defined in the Interval Data Links Resource. When this payload is delivered to the LwM2M server, via either a read request or a confirmed observation on this Object, Object Instance or Resource, the Latest Delivered Interval should for each of the Interval Data objects defined in the Interval Data Links Resource must be updated. When no new data exists for a specific Interval Data instance and empty Opaque value should be provided. When a specific Interval Data Instance is disabled (Recording Enabled Resource = 0), no payload data should be provided at all.]]></Description>
            </Item>
            <Item ID="3">
                <Name>Schedule</Name>
                <Operations>RW</Operations>
                <MultipleInstances>Single</MultipleInstances>
                <Mandatory>Optional</Mandatory>
                <Type>Objlnk</Type>
                <RangeEnumeration></RangeEnumeration>
                <Units></Units>
                <Description><![CDATA[The Schedule resource provides link to a schedule object. This Schedule object is used to provide fine grain control the Notification schedule delivery when the default LwM2M NOTIFICATION attributes do not provide sufficient control. If no schedule is required, an Object Link referencing no Object Instance will contain the concatenation of 2 MAX-ID values (null link).]]></Description>
            </Item>
        </Resources>
        <Description2></Description2>
    </Object>
</LWM2M>

